Jamie Henry

321-576-5440 | jamiehenry802@gmail.com | Mascotte, FL

Summary

Competitive and versatile software developer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Central Florida. Expertise in problem-solving and algorithm analysis driven by a passion for computers, technology, and video games. Over a decade of coding experience, specializing in developing mobile and web full-stack applications.

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://jayhenry07.github.io/
- linkedin.com/in/jamie-henry-8ba765154

Skills

Full-Stack Development, Spring Framework, REST APIs, Spring Boot, TypeScript, Java, Agile development methodologies, React

Experience

PwC (Contract)

Full Stack Developer | 08/2022 - Present

- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Collaborated with fellow engineers to evaluate software and hardware interfaces.
- · Developed unit test cases for testing and automation.

SkillStorm (Full-time)

Full Stack Developer | 05/2022 - Present

- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- · Developed functional databases, applications and servers to support websites on back-end.

BladeDocs (Freelance)

Mobile Application Developer | 03/2023 - Present

- Employed full-stack development tools to produce holistically envisioned applications for mobile devices.
- Tracked post-deployment bug reports to recognize and resolve trends among user-reported faults and complaints.

Education

University of Central Florida Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering | 05/2022

• 3.61 GPA

Lake-Sumter State College Associate of Arts in General Studies | 05/2019

• 3.94 GPA

Licenses and Certifications

- Java Foundations Certified Junior Associate Certification Oracle
- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- Back End Development and APIs freeCodeCamp
- Scientific Computing with Python freeCodeCamp

Honors and Awards

Mathematics Award

• Lake-Sumter State College, April 2019, For academic excellence and achievement in mathematics.

References

• Jamie is an excellent software developer, production designer, and systems architect. He makes impact effectively as an individual contributor, but not only that; he is also accomplished as a team lead and project manager. Jamie is first choice for senior engineering roles. A true maker and a doer. An objectively great hire.

(Skurhse Rage; April 20, 2024)

Jamie was the most technically competent and emotionally balanced individual that I had the pleasure to work with.
Besides his technical prowess, his ability to keep interactions fun and positive along with his ability to find creative
solutions to difficult problems were qualities that really stood out to me. Lastly, Jamie is not stingy at all with his
knowledge and is always willing to help and offer guidance to others. If I had to build a team of developers and
leaders, Jamie would certainly be at the top of my list.

(Neil Haleem; August 17, 2022)